Um...
How did Second Madam die?
Second Madam...
She broke the Demon-Revealing Mirror
and was haunted by an evil spirit.
Go see if Master is back yet.
Yes, Madam.
The Flower Demon killed someone!
Demon-Revealing Mirror, keep us safe.
Monsters and ghosts, be gone!
Alright, alright, alright.
Why wave a mirror around at this hour?
Let me tell you,
careful not to summon all three wives.
So,
Second Madam
was really crushed by the chandelier?
I saw it with my own eyes.
The chandelier came crashing right down.
Second Madam was such a beautiful woman,
yet she was crushed to pieces.
It was so tragic.
Don't wander around the manor at night.
If you run into Second Madam,
you'll be in trouble.
One night,
Xiaocui ran into Second Madam.
She was scared sick and is now bedridden.
Where did Second Madam live?
The West Wing.
Alright.
Let's go take a look.
Second Madam,
did you return from studying in France
and immediately marry into the Li family?
Do you
put on makeup every day before going out?
But why
would this chandelier
happen to fall right on you?
This vanity has been moved.
It should've been further inside,
but someone dragged it here.
Furniture moving late at night...
Someone must've tied a rope to drag it.
The furniture was dragged a bit each day.
Over time,
it ended up right under the chandelier.
Second Madam wasn't one for details,
so she wouldn't have noticed.
But this chandelier...
how did it fall out of nowhere
and happen to hit Second Madam?
Look here.
A scorched hemp rope.
If my deduction is correct,
the weapon used to kill Second Madam
must still be in this room.
What could the weapon be?
The murder took place
at 1:00 PM.
The angle of the sunlight
should be around 80 degrees.
If my deduction is correct,
the weapon used to kill Second Madam
is this magnifying glass.
An old book in Wenchang Pavilion says
that a magnifying glass
can focus light.
And the killer
used this principle
to focus sunlight into a single point.
Then, using the vanity mirror,
they reflected it onto the hemp rope,
causing the rope to burn
and the chandelier to fall.
I know about this!
If you point a magnifying glass at wood,
it'll catch fire in a bit.
So the killer used the room's furnishings
as a murder weapon.
They could kill without being present.
And before this,
they ran multiple experiments,
which is why the vase heated up
and shattered.
How did the stool Master sat on break?
To execute this plan precisely,
the killer even tampered with the rope.
To cut the hemp rope,
they stepped on and broke the stool.
Why would the killer go to such lengths
to kill Second Madam?
Dazhu.
Let me ask you something.
At 1:00 PM on the day Second Madam died,
did she arrange to meet Master at home?
Second Madam made some suits for Master.
She called him home to try them on.
Master had no choice but to agree.
Take care.
Okay.
But as Master was about to close shop,
someone came into the store.
I'm meeting my wife. I have to go.
Sir,
please come back later.
I have a big deal
that I can only discuss with you.
What big deal?
Master.
Master, terrible news!
Second Madam is dead.
What?
By a twist of fate,
Master Li escaped disaster yet again.
Mengzhu,
First Wife, Second Madam...
All three of them were scapegoats.
There's an evil spirit in this mansion.
Master is generous and charitable.
He is protected by the gods.
Good deeds are always rewarded.
Alright, alright.
Dazhu, go back to sleep.
Master.
Did you see a child in your vision?
He was right there.
On this wall...
it wasn't this painting before.
It was a wooden puppet.
And now this painting is here.
It seems
someone is guiding our investigation.
What do they want us to investigate then?